Apparently I'm starting with this slide.
So, if you have a...can do...codes can take a picture that and get
...on evaluation before you've heard me speak.
Which I'm okay with...may want to wait and see if I actually say anything you like?
But, forget started...has been working in software and...industry for five years.
Most people that's what ten years.
Twenty was still going twenty-five I feel like many...option here thirty.
Thirty thirty years example thirty is papal.
Now you don't have to have been doing this for thirty years you don't...been doing it for ten years to know that
your world is changed the software that web building is not the same software we used to
be building the...we're building it for not the same people the
...interface models and not the same the places we're putting the code
...deploying to are not the same the business models are not the same everything is changed.
And, hopefully your tools...been changing as well because those tools that
...using five ten thirty years ago
...not...not going to be working as well for the new models that we're dealing with.
Also in this time and now we're only looking back less than five years microsoft
...to this is a thing that you've been hearing throughout...you keep hearing the rest of the time
where doing things differently now when more open less secretive.
Contributing more open-source products web more permissive with the licensing
...more open to other platforms and other operating systems just a couple weeks ago
as up icon big python conference being held in montreal three thousand
...not a huge amount of microsoft fans there.
And, one of the really common things that I kept hearing over and over again people coming up to
make people coming up to...during the conference I
love the new microsoft I don't use windows but I love which you guys are doing.
I don't use visual studio but I love it.
A whole lot of people who have been noticing the changes that we've been making
and the differences that any effects...that is having on the software industry.
We've changed in this time we're actually getting things right.
What does this mean fear?
It means you're going to get better open-source software microsoft has been contributing to tools like
get to tools like...js php.
To make these run
better on windows so if you're working on windows you have access to better open-source software.
You're getting better platforms.
...contributions to linux making improvements to hype of a and
to our infrastructure so that these
opensource platforms well-run better for you so you can have just as good access to them as you would anywhere else.
And, you're getting better opensource tools.
The tools that we are building a being developed on different models
and a lot of cases which means there...there's more people involved
uses a directly involved in making these tools better in a way that they didn't used to be so they are better tools.
Now this is an ak notes let's get back down-to-earth this session I'm going to be
talking about python going to be talking about no js.
And, specifically how we support those in visual studio and also how we support the
measure.
I'm going to spend the next twenty minutes also talking and then I'm going
...individual studio and everything else is...demos so,
if you have questions come up with told them until the end of the talking bit just in case I get to them
and then from then on will be sitting at the demo machine and seeing some cool stuff.
So, what's...dot js and why do we care about it?
No, js is relatively on language
programming environment's probably a better term came about twenty nine twenty ten was starting
to come out it's javascript on the server.
It's javascript running on top of a really good javascript engine
...the veight engine that's came out of crime which
at the time was the best is the fastest ported to run on the server...to do server-side apps so it's a
young language but it has all the heritage of javascript and it also has all the future of javascript
a six comes along as seven comes along those getting rode back into node.
What this means is that you have...pull of developers...doing front-end development been doing
websites for a long-time who can now extend the scope they're not just front-end developers...full
stack developers because all the javascript I can already do they can now do on the server as well?
And, the cool thing about...js and this can only happen in...language is
...asynchronous from this dot they said nothing is going to block
no operation at all is going to stop the program from making progress.
If you're familiar with say shop, you know, as a
...await which is common fairly recently merge as had it from the beginning so everything
...everything is thoroughly asynchronous which makes it great at handling huge
quantities of parallel requests parallel operations with.
Fav fewer resources than other languages again...
What about python...and old language
...on twenty five years so now it's older than csharp...java?
But, it still has a very active development team
...constantly being improved constantly being worked on and it's in a
constant race with javascript and csharp...who can add this the best new features first.
And, for a long-time...being winning that race.
It's a very popular language for teaching
...very easy-to-read but it has all of the core concepts that are important
for teaching students how to program it has a full type system even though it
is dynamic typing means you don't spend all your time writing out type names.
And, it has a huge ecosystem of libraries and support basically every cloud provider out
there has python is one of the top
...languages for managing and controlling and deploying
today cloud systems and some of the library
...python...so big they have their own conferences libraries like...go libraries like
...have dedicated conferences
with attendance in the hundreds of thousands is not just little made up's.
And, microsoft has support for both of these languages.
Now get...yet this is not a product announcement.
This isn't some we've just decided we can start throwing
days out there and let you start using python...js
buttons had visual studio support to some extent since twenty ten.
That's five years.
That we've been shipping python extension for visual studio to give
you all of the support that I'm going to show you a bit later on...js has been available on
actually since twenty eleven even I was shocked by that when I went back to figure out when it first showed up.
That's four years we've had no js support on measure this is not something you this is
a serious commitment python no js and not disappearing from the things that we're doing.
And, then not ...brand new ideas or just throwing out the dasi when they stick...to
...the js or...out...for a developers.
And, that's why when I bring up a checklist of the features that we support for
these in visual studio it's fairly complete.
All the features you'd expect to find...visual...any other language
if you imagine a world where you installed visual studio and it just had python
...just had no js there...just expect all these features to be
the and they are we haven't left things out simply because
the different languages we've gone through and filled in all the gaps as best we can so that
...no js will give you...great editing great code completion
great debugging experiences and both of these both of our extensions are
...having the best debugging experiences out there for these two languages.
Profiling is...all of version control...visual studios available.
Remote debugging is a great feature that we've made available and that remote debugging
incidently is cross-platform remote debugging as well.
Because python...js are inherently cross-platform languages you're running that code on linux
you're running it on...you can remotely debugged from visual studio I'll show you that later on.
And, because this so heavily.
Supported by packages and libraries we have package management billion and this
is being developed head of an in sync with some of the...package management
...visual studio or some of it looks a bit different but it is effectively coming to the same
point and we are hoping to linking closer with the general visual studio supporter packages soon.
Become to leisure and again the pictures fairly complete.
This is not languages we've just spun up within working on this for a while all the web apps
with support python...js and have done fears?
Cloud service will course...you do that linux and windows
va m which are available and I'll show you can do whatever you want and that includes python and...js.
The storage services most of the platform services in fact the application
insides has a really great sdk from both languages document the base supports
both languages these are services that you can use today from python
...js and not feel like you're a second-class citizen this
...proper like first-class support for these languages.
And, machine learning which is one of...only recently.
Fully released has python support built into it and fact any other language
...machine learning right...and,...both open-source languages you
can't even you can't do dot net in that yet that's really rare for us what changing.
But, here's a question expected asking why would I use python.
Why would I...js when should I use that?
And, it's true there's nothing that you can do in these languages that can't be done
any of the other languages that you may be using.
Especially if...other languages csharp or dot net in general everything you can do in...python you can do
in net.
But, for some applications it's going to be easier it's going to be smoother it's going to be
faster it's going to
be more enjoyable to use a language that's a benefit for the task at hand.
Python is very good at dealing with glue code.
This is code that doesn't do a huge amount of processing itself but it's going to
call out to other libraries...calling out to other programs and telling them what to do.
Buttons often criticized for being slower and depending on which implementation which version of
python you get, yeah, it can run slower if you're doing intense processing but
if you get a library that can do really fast processing you can use python to tell that
...data processing...and suddenly that's not a bottleneck anymore.
Most cloud provide is have.
The management services...through python...case.
If you're on as you're if you're on a ws if
you're on choose your own provided this they will have a python library from managing
...systems spinning up the m coining images.
I'll show you some of that a little later on is highly portable if
you ever have code that you may need to run on a different operating system.
Python is very likely going to just work.
The guys behind of done
amazing job making sure that python works well on all the major operating systems.
Which means that when you're writing code that needs to be cross-platform it's always a good choice
was speaking to an engineer add a company I won't name a little
while ago who using python as a file system filter?
Because it's cross-platform so they've written
a cross-platform file system filter that's intercepting file system
...and changing...and rights and...written that...python because it's cross-platform.
And, it has powerful libraries why rewrite something when you can just get it from elsewhere python has one
of the best collections of libraries out there if there's something that you need
is probably there.
But, what about no js why would you use no js?
Because of its star...
in the way that's been set up it's really good at dealing with high-volume and low
latency requests much like a web server much like what we want for a web service.
Calling a glorified proxy is probably a bit of
a little bit unfair but on the other hand that's actually a really important
area of application for those of us that already have running code.
Whether api layering is a way of taking existing system you have and maybe it's a
crafty old java
app that's fifteen-years-old and spitting out really ugly xml and
you need a nice jason api with authentication and you don't want to
go back in touch all that old code because it works no js can common can be a proxy
right in the middle on that the public part of your api and suddenly you have a nice
modern web api without having to touch year-old legacy code.
And, because the asynchronous built-in because it's so deeply ingrained
in the language it's actually makes no js...good candidate for internet of things.
Low-power devices need the ability to
suspend the hardware when it's not doing anything and when...js
integrated that closely a knows that it's not doing anything it can switch
into low-power...far more efficiently than a lot of other languages can?
That's enough talk.
I have demos and not...activity here to longer for...do that...anyone want to bring up any questions.
And, this isn't really about the top the top of to the course but...happened iron python.
So,...and python is very happily living out in the community now
...that was so for those who don't know I and python was a separate implementation of python,
python being the...see python being the
most commonly used implementation of that language.
...python with an alternative implementation really good interfacing with dot net
...code made it really transparent really nice but,
it was a project that we found was not as beneficial for...team was working on
at the time and rather than simply killing it which is you...back in back in the
david's what normally would have happened we...and on so there's people out
in the community as a community grown-up around I'm python who lovett...supporting
...actively developing it they are making releases not
incredibly frequently but they are still goings-on python still live...still going and,
we've actually.
Basically completely with the hands of it and it's going fine without a help
...support right now.
Ok, so, I have three demos that I'm going to go through.
As I said any of these could be done in any language of your
choice and the fact that I've chosen a particular language for each one doesn't necessarily mean
that's the best choice it's the choice that I made so you could do...in different languages if you want to.
The first we're going to look at is some...management so I have a scripts that I'm going to
what I'm going to add a few bits to and walking through how it works and what it's doing we're going...
Basically input automated process so let's say my business has
some task once a month maybe once a week someone has to go out and spin-off
virtual machine install some software into it run some process
get the results and then kill of machine because we...charge money for having that there all the time.
This is...this really easy to automate through as using a python script
in this case and the python sdk for...and its management api.
I'm not explicitly going-to demo visual studio to
you guys I assume you've seen it before so,
I'll be implicitly demo ing hole itself as I go through this.
But, I don't feel the need to insult your intelligence by saying look,
you can type stuff and it changes color
...I can have...my mouse over it and get to tips.
So, this is a code I have here.
One of the things that I have done already because it's always worth doing before you come in
for live demo is installed the as...package.
So, python has a few concepts and package management the one that I'm using
...virtual environment which is
project specific packages so they get install just for this project is not
especially important for this case and if you want more details...to a video at the end
they can help you understand...but pre installed the as...package and from
the of imported in fact I'll show you this.
Service management I have imported there's a whole lot of classes a whole
lot of functions and by importing...just getting all of them.
There's a bit of boiler plate here but eventually we're going to end up with
...certificate in open ssl format because that's what python works best with
...subscription id theorized subscription these
published settings file has just come up as you're...the...functions from aris
...to help you get that all into the right format so you can do it once and then forget about it...
You can see the commented...code that's why I remember what
...type but I'm going to type it because that can help...of visual studio for...
So, we work with an instance of the service management service which is a great name right.
And, when I create is...subscription id which I've already got?
Which I'll get from that said file constant?
And, now this is given me.
An object with a whole lot of commands
and this is where most of these commands come from sewer creating virtual machines
...images the lading images getting details listing the services that
I have basically anything you can do through the algebra portal you can do through this sdk.
I'm setting up a few constance here for creating the mission for creating machine first thing I'm going to create
...hosted service.
Because by doing this gives my virtual machine someone to live-and-let-live inside service so that if I want to
switch between production staging deployments I have sort of one benefit motor live...
Not only operations of function calls and some of
these a complicated function calls which means I have a lot of parameters some of upwards of twenty,
twenty five parameters to these function codes you don't have to specify all of them typically but
in some cases...because this is python has a really neat feature where you can set up
a dictionary full of the parameters and the values and
then possum dictionary so I can set up most of my configuration like this.
All I could have been...this from a file python as a lot of in
builtfile pauses this configure positive any type files that has
jason as xml...packages for...is packages for anything you can think of
so for this example I'm using a dictionary of configuration you could do this any other way.
And, then setting up most of the country here I'm not going to
buoyed by typing this up we're setting up a windows machine.
Was setting up some endpoints because I'm going to...to hit
...http server that thirty running on this and when I was debugging I wanted to be
...remote desktop into the machine and figure out why it wasn't
working so I had that one there but we don't really need that now because everything's going to work perfectly?
It's a...I can add more parameters in...and, they were going to my configuration.
...actually create virtual machine.
Instead of typing out all the parameters.
...deployment instead of filling out all these parameters can do double...and
...configure...this dictionary every single
...is the name of a parameter and fill in the value for those parameters.
And, it's and asynchronous operation it's mostly arrest api with some operations
take longer than http requests will allow so...functionality
and here to wait for an operation to complete which is this...for operation status.
I have some boiler play code...wait for things to get started.
And, in fact I'll show you that because I'll start running.
And, now we're in debug mode...debugging this script so it's going to start spitting out output here bring it up the.
And, what this vm image that I'm using actually does?
Should...output?
What is the...image amusing actually does is it has a...compiler...stowed so it's not just
a plain old...has a...compiler and has a basic web app running on it so I can
spin up this pm and say hey here's a python package that includes some
c code that I need a compiler...want to install use this package?
So, I don't have so I doing this I do on this machine but I'm going to
insource package on thousand machines and they don't...
to say compiler so by using this virtual machine I can spin up
a machine with...compiler quickly build the package and then take
the result and publish that all these other machine so I don't actually need a compiler on each of them.
And, to do that...exposes basically a web service so
when the virtual machine is created and running again...request
...request that says hey you do this will command on the package flask.
An understanding that from python...line of code just a simple get request.
Then I'm going to...in the browser so we can say some results coming in and
...we're just going to kill of the machine because the longer the machine is running for the more we get charged.
I considered not showing...because everything up to this point has been completely free.
And, the virtual machine running is how we make money but if you kill it really quickly we don't make as much money
...here so if you want to leave it running feel free but,
you probably one...kill it off as quickly as you can.
Ok, so, windows...so the time between starting the machine and it actually running and being able
to respond to a web request may take a little while.
And, I got through my explanation a little bit quicker than at...
So, that is still going but it is working which is a positive
sign anytime you doing a demo.
So, other things that you may use this sort of process for this is the sort of thing where
you maybe you have a task...once a month you need to grab a huge amount of daughter out of the way
house somewhere and process and you need a really big base machine we have virtual machines on as
...that have what...it four hundred
megabytes of ram and we'll give you five terabytes of ss day?
And, if you're working with a huge data set.
That's the sort of machine that this can actually help you with but it's not a machine you want to
...running all the time.
Unless you really want to give us...money in which case feel free...caped running all the time but,
you don't want to...that machine running all the time you want spin it up and spend five minutes to
...processing and then shutdowns
quick as possible this is ideal for that.
Because when this machine starts up it's going to run what...startup
...has you can automate the entire process.
Now the...ready and we hit the brake point here so I can see the url.
Where the machine is at adjoining that and we're going to do a request so that's nice and
quick to get to trigger the process and now spin up the web browser?
Which is simply showing me a list of how much of flask build so-if us
...refresh?
We should sit...packages appearing here.
So, this is downloaded some packages of the python package index
its compiling them and putting them into a redistribute of performant coda we'll.
...safe is the one the of interest because this has compiled
see module in it may not be...to say that on the screen but that file of highlighted is a
compiled module that we just built with the compiler on that machine now it's
in zip file so I can just copied onto the machines that need it and none of them the compiler.
And, back here we're just going to delete the
...the...deployment...operation and clean-up...service.
And, then we'll be done that virtual machine that we just created
run some task and now destroyed
probably ten twenty cents worth of time.
And, this is automated so you haven't even had to pay someone to sit here and do this?
So, when you've got operations that need a separate machine or need
high processing requirements this is a great way to automate being out...run anti process?
I want to throughout any questions about that one suggest anything else media...from move on.
So, next demos a web api wrap-up.
As I mentioned that's...js glorified proxy is.
A little unfair but still completely accurate at the same time so we're going to do that here I
have an old crafty api that's actually written in python because it was
quick.
And, it's returning big chunky xml data from some internal
system that I've got that I don't really want to go in this about with the code at this point.
I do want to expose it as jason I do want to expose it in a way that other people can get
what and use it and the other thing that I really want to do is fix-up as annoying to digit years
in the dates and make it a nice.
Portable date
format that people outside of the us can understand because they got the month...the day the right way around.
...that sound bill that wasn't meant...
So, this is the across the api...python code.
It's just the sake of a demo.
And, just...the sake of demonstrating I've got a basic little thing here that's just going to show
you some of the data that's inthis is what sending back this is the api that
I'm telling my mobile developers you have to use this you have to write a web page
...some javascript to
figure this out and display all of that information there.
Sand this data...third...third of july node.
I'm going to go through this and I'm and I have a cloud service here.
All of the support...in visual studio already is going to work for...node.
Because we've made it work with extended on top of the video studio support so it
can not sure how to do a web up with python node.
You actually just make a web project and then exactly the same ways
...directly to...say publish the same thing here we have a cloud service so I want
to web role in this case I'm going to add a new role project.
And, go to know js.
And, just make a web role.
This will give me a basic node application complete with a bright point a basic
node application that I can start coding and to make a web app that's
going to forward incoming requests onto that can server and reprocess...on the way out.
To help me out here I might have free written some of these and I'm going to do some copy taste.
So, every time the notepad window pops up just close your eyes.
Starting with some requires no js has a whole lot of
packages as well and these absolutely essential if you're
going to be working with it and the require statement is how you bring those
in will actually give you suggestions when you start requiring stuff.
Just like in python when you type import rule display of the packages you can import will give you the
full list of everything that's there for...u.
And, the first one of these I'm going to use is the url.
Package because I need to do some pausing on the
request this function taking...and res is going to handle every single incoming
request to this process.
So, I need to be out of rout these around a hundred different ways you can do url routing in
...doing it fairly simply just using the route package because I don't have that many to deal with.
The first thing I'm going to do is pull the path name out of the url.
So, urls...function and
then wrecked euro and that should give me a path name back.
That is going to be the name of the path so everything after
the in my case local host import everything after the host is going to be in the path name.
You can cheat grab some code.
Because what we do here is we call through into these routes so the routing module...the path
match module more specifically let me define basically some comparisons effectively
array x that also doesn't parameter substitution so when I
say let's get the parameters from...summary from path name it's going to
match user and then put id into a property which you can see right here.
We had then going-to-take that property positive function that I haven't written yet.
That is going to get the user info out of that extracted and give us back
this data object which...jason and return to the user so this is the
...functionality of the proxy.
We're getting we're going to get the data for a certain id and we're going to reprocess
it into something that is javascript
the converted to jason and res that end we'll send it back as a response the request.
This function that I need is going to get user infer.
Well-taken id.
And, because it's.
...we are thoroughly asynchronous so with my function I get the input
parameter which is id and I also get a call back function which are code dot...because we're going to call it when I've got the
infer I m sure there is a
good style name for that but I don't actually know what it is for this case
got info seems to work...
And, the first thing we're going to do is to go straight to and http get.
So, again, ok, apparently call backs a good name for it that's what I shape uses.
We're going to do...inside this get...going to take more code from here.
We're going to...in this case a really poorly hard coded reference to the old api.
But, this may be exactly what you do if you're owed api is an old program you
don't want to touch with the system it's running on is fine maybe you want to
deploy this proxy on the same machine and then you...just forwarding requests...local host.
And,...avoiding a lot of network bandwidth so you don't actually have any sort of
slowdown by injecting a node layer in front of your own api.
And, again, this is a synchronous this function with
...response is going to be code when the request is completed.
The first thing we need to check is whether it failed because of the status code is not equal to two hundred.
Then we wantcold call back immediately and you can
say that this call back function is expecting to get the status...expecting to get
...data that we have in this case we only have the status because it's a failure so
we just...that in and then we'll get out of here.
And, now we know that at this point our...succeeded we have
useful information from the old service that we can start transforming into jason.
This code took me awhile to get...so I'm definitely not typing onstage.
He likes x path.
I didn't think so.
But, it's actually not a bad choice for doing this so what I've done is I've
grab the xml dom package and the x path package.
Actually xml...might be standard think about it...
...these to packages to help me posse xml because I really.
Don't want to be doing this client-side I don't have to be rely on xml pausing client-side if
...all possible so I'm doing that here on the server?
There's a bit of boiler plate code effectively forgetting all of the data out
of the request is asynchronous so you need call backs that will
...repeatedly being cold until everything's complete.
And, then I simply posit document from the string from the response and just define
an object.
So, this use a objected of created has all of these properties as a balance it has a history it has
an id has a name we've recognized all of these properties.
On the object from this definition.
And, we should in fact even though the...because we've called to string on everything.
And, this gives us a javascript object that we then pasta got infer.
So, then the result of good info which should be here.
Is going-to-take that...that make it into jason and return?
And, that shooting...done everything right should be enough.
js layer no, it's not enough it's not enough because I have...stony packages yet.
So, no, js has a convention of a...file.
Which includes a list of all the dependencies that your package needs?
The nice thing about these is that when you go to publisher package
on to and pm which is the package repository you need to provide this file when you're building a project you need to
have this file so if you've worked on any
no js code at all you have something that can be published which means there's a lot of code
that's been published you have a lot of choices when it comes to doing basically anything in the js.
Now if you're watching you'll notice that after I added those dependency lines we suddenly showed up with a few
missing dependencies here so I can simply install missing and pm packages to go off and get all of those.
Another...soda now when I start running the code.
We running successfully and of jumped over to our new api page.
Which I already have urls here so this is the old?
This is the old xml that we don't ever want to
sagan and in just a small amount of node code we suddenly have
jason that can be easily possum the client can be...any browser
any mobile device tablet pc.
Gaining consul anything that can render a web page cannot...and display that information.
What have I done I haven't...the dates?
So, that's how we go...that.
The point where handling the date is right here.
...have an...selects and just getting the date from the use of converting into a strength.
...I'm going to write a function code fixed...so just call it that.
And, now...function fix state and weary recognize...string.
So,...just...function low type definitions we...the information through or from the
...site down below it so we can tell you that.
This parameter has all of these members on it because we know it's a strength.
Little bit of basic javascript code...it up will...on the
twenty...start...the year and then we'll reformat in into a data object which
when we convert jason is going to look far more.
Readable and nb from a portable.
And, just...break points and actually step through some of this time and see what we get.
So, again, couple great points hit...five.
And, within the first request come in I can
...the url and say the request is coming through and it's...for the slash.
Which is not going to...that it's not going to matches summary
it matches home which is where we get the welcome to our api from?
Now this time
when I hope over here now we've come back in and the and url in this case is use a one-oh-one.
After we posit into programs.
Can say we have the idea here which is one-oh-one which is the...trying to get sorry for that being so small?
And, now we fallen out because
...that we've made is asynchronous so the next step doesn't happen until it's ready for
it to happen and now skip to head of it so way into
the point after the request of the back-end api has come through.
Or about pussy upwards
...the output which is the xml...I'm actually let me bring that up in the xml visualize
of to show that if you want to look at xml inside visual studio we can format nicely for
And, we can in fact through that for a few other formats as well none of which makes sense
and xml string but we have an html and jason visualize a as well as just a
plain-text.
Visualize which
will show you the current state of your program in a way that makes sense and helpful fear.
And, this time when I
step in wave ended up inside the xbox module.
Which looks like a scary place to basal let's not do that?
And, our and fix state.
Inside here we can say the strings for twenty fifteen.
We split we have an array.
With adjusted the year so,
now the years has twenty fifteen and we can pass into the elements for...
And,...you dates.
And, now we've got the infer so now we're going to...string...the data.
And, hopefully at some point we get.
Here's the data so now I have jason's I can previous with adjacent visualize and,
this one's even more advanced we've got nice
tree view we can actually search through defined properties that we want to look at inside the
...all inside visual studio while I'm debugging this program.
And, now when I continue out...say the dates...formatted unambiguous
...it's even figured out that it was seven o'clock in the morning.
And, we know that this is in fact
...twelve and not the twelve another third of december.
So, that's no js one anyone ask anything about the from move on.
Can you do this and piping yes you can what recommended
probably not the some libraries that will give you high-volume request a
high-frequency requests in python just as well as no js handles them but they're not
...interlanguage in the same way no js is ideal for this kind of...
So, it's going to be a good choice.
For my final trick.
This is more an interesting demo of the visual studio support.
Then something you
might actually decide to do as a result of having being to this session
...the last two things have inspired your in some interesting ways that maybe you can automate
...processes without spending a huge amount of time developing the
tool for it or maybe you can make that old horrible api something that people actually want
to use this one's a little bit just more fun.
And, something that if you're already using these sorts of things
then you may find this usefully may find this really appealing and definitely a lot of people have told us this
is a great value and for the stuff that doing so I have a python script running on a linux machine.
Why is
running on linux machine because it has some dependency that one work on windows?
That's not strictly the case for this demo but it may be the case is absolutely feasible that
...some tool some program that you need to be
running on linux that cannot be run on windows so you have a script that's doing it.
But, something is not working properly and that script is not working very well.
And,...a python script so the
...choices...go...out a whole lot of logging to try and figure out what's going on
all you can dive in and try and use one of the regular python debug is
or use one of the linux important python debugging none of which are
as good to uses visual studio so this is the third option
which is let's enable remote debugging on the linux machine so that we can connect
...from visual studio and get all the benefits all the functionality of
...without having to without having to move the code somehow to a local machine.
So, I'm going to start on my machine just show you what's going on.
Here's my script what's actually doing is taking some my holiday photos
and creating thumbnails for them.
So, I put a whole lot of photos up in some measure storage blobs.
And, it's downloading the photo it's running it through
an image processing library which is my only works on linux example fitted I it actually works
...windows but for this...it's running on linux.
...creating thumbnails for them you can say it's printing out
...eras when I cancel it...printing out...of urls.
So, the first url...printing out is just to remind me which one it's gotten.
And, there's my image this is from my last trip...
That's a tram in fact you probably know about those because they have kind of things like them hidden
...san francisco that's
...tram very nice way of getting around.
And, here is the thumb now that we've generated.
For that and you can see the differences with actually put it in a
different contain up with the same name.
So, the steps...descriptive gone through in fact I bring up the code that I can show you.
Just like before we createdso, from the actual library we imported
the service management service before the some using a bob service because we're dealing with blobs...storage.
...listing them and here out to container definitions bit of code to just create goes but then the
...we're going to this container and we listing all the blobs that there is giving
us details about everything that's already in that container which in this case is all of my holiday photos.
All of the holliday photos I wouldn't be worried to have appear on stage and build.
Be clear.
And, then we're doing...get love to butts that's going to often download that image and just loaded into memory so now we have
...jpeg in memory...a python script.
And, this imaged open is the library this libraries code
...il python image...if you want to installed you actually install
pillar these days there was a dispute about compatibility and
...at some point and these days pillow is the one that works but,
this is just a really nice simple image processing library for python.
So, we'll open that from the in memory file grab the size of...we're going to crappie image into a square.
We're going to run edge enhancement because I thought that might be a good idea looking at the thumbnails
it isn't but it might have been.
I'm guilty of not updating my comments because we're going to resize to hundred-fifty by hundred-fifty which.
Is...on now?
Finally we put the data back into a...io which is
an in memory buffer memory stream effect.
And, then put the block lowball from that in memory stream and push that back up to
either into a different container
never print messages it's fairly simple it's actually working completely fine right now the
job is doing is fine because I couldn't come up with a good bug for to have but we're going-to go ahead and debugged anyway.
So, a couple of things we need to do to and I would debugging.
First.
We need to import and install pst.
...visual studio...
This is a module that I don't have installed locally but I don't
...on this machine because it's only going to be running on the remote wishing.
This will let me set up a socket connection so that I can connect into the running process.
There's a whole lot of parameters you can specify
...the first one unspecified is the secret which is a password.
So, if you've been paying attention you could now be attaching...you can't yet after
I publish this change you could be attaching to the my process before I get...please don't do that...going to
spoil the demo but you could be because you've now...the sacred and as you anything keeping you out.
And, then we're...wait for...you don't have to do this but this is convenient if you're planning to debug from the
start of the code it's just going to hold up until you've actually attach the debug.
Another publish this.
...prompt.
This is a crazy command so I wrote into a batch file.
And, that's just uploaded using
...of just transfer the file over sh and now it's
...the machine if I pull up nano demo here you can say that we've now
got this code has been updated.
The next...actually so pbs day because I don't have it on this machine yet.
...is a package management
...pippen stole is going to install the package dashed...free is going to install pre
release versions which I need because I'm running python two-point-two ossie.
So, it needs a slightly newer version them you'd normally install if you didn't put a dash
...because you get...one for...to python tools two-point-one.
This is going to go often install the package.
And, once this is done I can just start running the script again.
And, will be good to set will be go-to...have a look?
And, this time you...not doing anything it's waiting for me to attached.
Come back to visual studio.
...debug I can attach to process.
Python remote debugging is
...transport we want to use here and as a bit of an explanation how-to-do-it connecting of a...
Machine secret that build demos the mthree.
I could of...different port but I haven't and, in fact I should mention this because
I'm not actually prepared to show right now when you set this up you need to
enable the endpoint if you're on a measure virtual machine or in fact most cloud
...they're not going to be opening this port for public access so-if you have
an open that port for public access into virtual machine ...that's creating
...endpoint then you're not...be out of connect but assuming everything's
okay when you hit enter in this box you'll see a list of the running python processes on that machine and it's telling me it's a
python three five linux sixty four-bit and I'm going to touch and now we're running.
I can jump back over here and it's taking me back because...a break point.
So, while I'm broken here I can hover of any variable I want
and see all the details just like I would if it was running locally.
You can step overusing f ten I can see and fact not going to look at data for that.
I can inspect this image.
I can say from the type of jpeg image file I can see all the information that I couldn't...before without the
package installed but now because on live debugging on a remote machine...sending back all the information
and asking for to see what's going on in my code you.
For...spin background the...can say that it got the blob did the first one.
And, in fact it's also displaying the output here so everything...screen it's going to display
writing visual studio there's no need to be switching back and forth to the original process.
Now as a step through this is doing image processing and as a few steps involved so maybe I want to look
at the image at some various points along the way I'm just perform the
crop so now I m is crop but another way to look at image until we get to this code that's going to save it.
So, what I'm going to do with this code instead of waiting is I'm going to copy it
and open what we call the debug interactive windows so under debug windows python debug interactive?
And, this is a...
I need to...is a...show where I can write arbitrary python code
such as let's say this startup to buy player and then put into a blog.
I can get the...I can make the blob url.
Target container same name and this will show me this is where it's gone ahead
and put the partially process photo if I open that up
...say it's a nice big photo because that's what side of that but it's been...
If I come back to this scripting continue
...so let's stepped over the filter now we
filter the image so I can come back up here rerun this bit of code which is going to
take the image now live put it back up on the blob storage...same name.
And, I may have just messed that up by hitting the wrong refresh button.
And, I think that's been enhanced.
Both come background we should have the...this probably.
...process so let's try that one again with the next image.
So, crop well-run the filter.
Narrow to photo disdain.
So, we've put this into thumbs...for fifteen.
Which will be the edge enhanced version
it's also this rotated sideways version that's actually a staircase?
Resize step and now we can run the same code again.
And,...refresh it's been resize so we're actually interfering with the program
...executing arbitrary code on the remote machine part way through a program running this is a great
way to be able to figure out what's wrong with code without actually having to sit on the linux box itself or
sachin toward and work through everything step-by-step they don't have any questions about that from of on.
So, the question is effectively is this running in the same environment so that's why I can just pick up
log in this stuff nor it's not like this code is all running on
a machine over and as...land somewhere I'm not exactly sure where.
The machine is build demo...mthree dot
...up dot net if you want to de os it and bring it down...welcome to do that now because I'm done.
This is running off into data center somewhere and
...urls ...urls you can go to one of these and check...the photos if you want.
These open-to-the-public internet and I'm actually pushing public photos...as
storage as part of this demo so this is not fate this one is a real demo.
Ok, here a couple of links which...photo but they're not that...to forget.
Our python tools for visual studio and node js
...visual studio or there's a way you can get to the overview pages and those will
lead you through the other things you need to download and install as well as get
you into some videos and overviews of what is used for and what we're actually doing with them
at microsoft?
The last...if you're not sick of hearing me talk already
...series we recently...is an introductory so from absolute first
principles getting set up with visual studio or python tools python.
And, then using the editor the debug all the way through some really advanced
...debugging like I just showed mixed...see and python debugging which is
really cool we have a whole video series of that that's that length.
What has changed?
Everything's different...doing different things.
Different things require different tools.
You can't use the one tool...matter how great it is...every task you have to do.
No, js and python a powerful flexible additions to this toolbox.
To slider
...be prepared for cross-platform is becoming so much more important these days.
You are doing yourself a disservice if you're not thinking about how you may be out
to be working with other...
Your entirely looked in on windows sooner or later that's going to...by...
No, js python.
Are already cross-platform if your code is in those languages it will work on other platforms?
It's a free way to get that benefit.
Without having to work too hard.
And, finally this assign you here you'll be hearing a lot of build.
Consider embracing opensource.
It's been...microsoft has been getting the is taken time we've been getting there.
When now interacting with open-source and positive ways
...directly contributing to a huge amount of projects?
We have a huge number of developers actively working with open-source projects
and open-source communities and it's so worthwhile these days open-source
software is where the knowledge of software engineering is...it's not journals
snot university courses...in the software that's out there
for everyone to say so please be part of that use it
...to and build on top of it contribute back to...support...
Anyone have any final questions.
You'll be out of find me for the rest of the evening after I've eaten at the languages birth
on the third-floor so-if you want to come...more I'll be there thanks account.